# Jeremy L. Shepherd

# **Full Stack Developer**

Xenia, Ohio

github.com/jeremylshepherd jeremylshepherd.github.io

#### **About Me**

### How I got into coding

In 2014, I wanted to have a website to showcase my photography. I started with WordPress templates but never found one that spoke to me. I decided to learn enough coding to build my own webpage. Eventually, I landed on Codecademy's site. I took one class, then two, then three... until I had taken nearly every course on the site. I was hooked and have been since. I have expanded my knowledge and built several projects. I enjoy the challenge of solving problems with code.

# **Skills Summary**

- React
- React Native
- Angular
- NodeJS

- ExpressJS
- MongoDB/SQL
- Ruby-on-Rails
- Git

# **Current Project**

Building a React-Native Client to interface with my citation tracking application

### **Professional Experience**

2003-Present Good Samaritan Hospital Dayton, OH

#### **Campus Police Officer (Sergeant)**

- Promoted to Sergeant in 2008
- Managed a small team of professionals
- Built the citation tracking application now used by the department.

2000–2005 Kroger Xenia, OH

#### **Loss Prevention Agent**

Self scheduled and self managed

1999–2006 Cedarville Police Dept. Cedarville, OH

#### **Police Officer**

Functioned with limited direct supervision in a field that demands a high level of accountability

1999–2000 Wilberforce Univ. Police Dept. Wilberforce, OH

#### **Campus Police Officer**

Functioned with limited direct supervision in a field that demands a high level of accountability

#### **Education**

- Senior, BCJ Program (Ohio University, Inactive)
- AAS Criminal Justice (Sinclair Community College
- Free Code Camp Completed Front-End, Data Visualization, and Back-end Certifications.